[{"id": "5fe8f86a01dd7bf43be5e842", "question": "Where were U.S. coins with an \"O\" on them minted?", "answer": "New Orleans", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abb2", "question": "What US state has a Thames River?", "answer": "Connecticut", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59f9b885364247bf200fb881", "question": "The Easter lily is a native plant of which country?", "answer": "Japan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3a6", "question": "What continent includes Iran?", "answer": "Asia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396fc", "question": "Who was the King of Swing?", "answer": "Benny Goodman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133995c", "question": "Who were the two villains in the movie \"Batman Returns\"?", "answer": "The Penguin and Catwoman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5937ed1e08d98002fdd633c4", "question": "The 1976 Summer Olympics were held in which city?", "answer": "Montreal", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf7a", "question": "How many pockets are there on a snooker table?", "answer": "Six", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a585", "question": "Which of the New England states is the largest in size?", "answer": "Maine", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc55", "question": "Who was the first woman to head the International Montary Fund?", "answer": "Christine Lagarde", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb3b", "question": "What are the three yellow properties on the standards Monopoly board?", "answer": "Marvin Gardens, Atlantic Avenue and Ventnor Avenue", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c639", "question": "What does uranium become when it has lost all of its radioactivity?", "answer": "Lead", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff0b6bde662d71a5365100d", "question": "Who named a urinal \"Fountain\" and exhibited it in 1917?", "answer": "Marcel Duchamp", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6014c8defbde8045e48466e2", "question": "What do plants produce through photosynthesis?", "answer": "Plants use energy from the sun to turn carbon dioxide into food. Carbohydrates and oxygen are the end result of photosynthesis.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339716", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", Homer gave up his soul for a single what?", "answer": "Doughnut", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a7d", "question": "What historical woman has been portrayed on stage and screen by Faye Dunaway, Elaine Paige, and Madonna?", "answer": "Eva Peron", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390a5", "question": "The character Lieutenant Pinkerton appears in what opera?", "answer": "Madama Butterfly", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339dba", "question": "Until their 2007 breakup, Peter Hook spent almost three decades as the bassist for what band?", "answer": "New Order", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4ce", "question": "What European art museum has a glass pyramid in its courtyard?", "answer": "The Louvre", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b194", "question": "What year did Napoleon become King of Italy?", "answer": "1805", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe65732ae7e414034b5aed8", "question": "In medieval England, what was used as currency, specifically for rental agreements?", "answer": "Eels", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fea8145ff048f679a45ac1f", "question": "What is the fastest ocean fish?", "answer": "Sailfish", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395f2", "question": "In The Simpsons, what colour is Ralph's belt buckle?", "answer": "Red", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "600cc1ac6de0eb824d4052e1", "question": "The U.S. Virgin Islands are located in which Ocean?", "answer": "Atlantic Ocean", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fea8025ff048f679a45ac18", "question": "What period did the Tyrannosaurus Rex live during?", "answer": "Cretaceous", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133895e", "question": "What was Cinderella's real name?", "answer": "Ella", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9de", "question": "If you were travelling at Mach II how fast would you be moving?", "answer": "Twice the speed of sound\u00a0", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a040", "question": "According to Peter, what is a \"cripple's natural enemy\", in the TV show \"Family Guy\"?", "answer": "The fence", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c569", "question": "How many blowholes does a southern right whale have?", "answer": "2", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58be2d788faf425cf37add7e", "question": "The game \"Cities: Skylines\" was developed by which Finnish video game company?", "answer": "Colossal Order", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c708", "question": "Dry ice is the frozen form of what gas?", "answer": "Carbon dioxide", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59e3f4135cb9e8bda6821366", "question": "By what other name is the folk tale \"Cinderella\" also known as?", "answer": "The Little Glass Slipper", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe6989820565ad31a57c735", "question": "Odysseus was the king of what island in the Mediterranean Sea?", "answer": "Ithaca", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe8aa7401dd7bf43be5e75b", "question": "What is the marketing term for the Monday after Thanksgiving day in the USA?", "answer": "Cyber Monday", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397c2", "question": "Who said of his TV fame: \"To this day, people will call me Dan Arnold.\"?", "answer": "John Goodman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133babe", "question": "What is the five-letter term for a rabbi who performs ritual circumcisions?", "answer": "Mohel", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339598", "question": "Wesley Snipes and Woody Harrelson work as hustlers in what 1992 film?", "answer": "White Men Can't Jump", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397db", "question": "Which US actor with a stage name of Edward was born in Romania as Emmanuel Goldenburg?", "answer": "Edward G. Robinson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fb0882bcf631c2414a13b5a", "question": "What does \"Valar Morghulis\" mean in High Valyrian?", "answer": "All men must die", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa17", "question": "What country borders Egypt to the south?", "answer": "Sudan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e16", "question": "What cartoonist of \"Maus\" also created \"Topps Garbage Pail Kids\"?", "answer": "Art Spiegelman", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338dda", "question": "From what language did English borrow the word \"ukulele\"?", "answer": "Hawaiian", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5e9", "question": "Where is the Bay of Pigs?", "answer": "Cuba", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff2597d31a458464a93c46c", "question": "Which U.S. city is home to a giant replica of Babe Ruth\u2019s baseball bat?", "answer": "Louisville, Kentucky", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe8b76401dd7bf43be5e7e3", "question": "What dog breed has the most Best in Show wins at the Westminster Dog Show?", "answer": "Wire Fox Terrier", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abb7", "question": "What was Malawi formerly known as?", "answer": "Nyasaland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe8b2bb01dd7bf43be5e7a2", "question": "A group of ferrets is called what?", "answer": "A business", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c97f", "question": "What constellation is represented by scales?", "answer": "Libra", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6015ea40fe83fe1f2a824bef", "question": "In 2007, purported remains of what saint were found to be from an Egyptian mummy instead?", "answer": "Joan of Arc", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133924b", "question": "Who performed the Bond theme song \"Die Another Day\"?", "answer": "Madonna", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1bf", "question": "What US president was a personal friend of Sam Houston?", "answer": "Andrew Jackson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59e6b627fb6c85e9e634ff47", "question": "Androphobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Males, or men", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5b3231d3bf195a31e15d7388", "question": "Also known as the \"Chile Pine\", what is the common name of the tree \"Araucaria araucana\"?", "answer": "Monkey puzzle", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133958f", "question": "What is the name of the genetically modified disease in the movie \"Mission: Impossible II\"?", "answer": "Chimera", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339222", "question": "As a child, what did Casper the Friendly Ghost die from?", "answer": "Pneumonia", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a438", "question": "In what country is the San Andreas Fault located?", "answer": "United States", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ab99cd621a8909e5c332d3b", "question": "What is the capita of Corsica?", "answer": "Ajaccio", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be4f", "question": "In 2005, what product reintroduced its catchphrase \"I can't believe I ate the whole thing\"?", "answer": "Alka-Seltzer", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fea3ccbff048f679a45ab43", "question": "What does the name \"lagomorph\" refer to?", "answer": "Rabbit", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fefc4206ce05a3942286f2d", "question": "What is the name of the ramrod in the television series \"Rawhide\"?", "answer": "Rowdy Yates", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe9f165ff048f679a45aab1", "question": "How do crocodiles keep cool?", "answer": "They release heat through their mouths", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e4a", "question": "What athlete had a part in the movie \"Action Jackson\"?", "answer": "Carl Weathers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339edb", "question": "What position was first held by Steve Allen?", "answer": "Tonight Show host", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a08", "question": "What snack shares its name with the famous cartoon strip by Charles M. Schulz?", "answer": "Peanuts", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4fd", "question": "What do you get when you mix white rum, lime juice, mint and sugar?", "answer": "A Mojito", "category": "general"}, {"id": "601b4bff49076251badbeacb", "question": "Which U.S. President had the most children?", "answer": "John Tyler -- The 10th president had 16 children \u2014 15 with his two wives and one born out of wedlock.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe7c4af877e98cb977789a3", "question": "Which two African countries merged into Tanzania?", "answer": "Tanganyika and Zanzibar", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59e6b84ffb6c85e9e634ff4e", "question": "What nationality is golfer Paul Azinger?", "answer": "American", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5963726b967692ea851899bf", "question": "Approximately 95% of the jellyfish's body is made up of what?", "answer": "Water", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395d8", "question": "In The Simpsons, what hangs on the wall directly to the right of the refridgerator in the Simpson's kitchen?", "answer": "Telephone", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d31", "question": "In the 1956 western, what actress are The Searchers searching for?", "answer": "Natalie Wood", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133977b", "question": "Where is the film Predator set?", "answer": "South American jungle", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f79", "question": "In music what is meant by \"pianissimo\"?", "answer": "Very soft", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339460", "question": "What silent film star was \"The Tramp\"?", "answer": "Charlie Chaplin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a012", "question": "What director played a psychiatrist's psychiatrist on \"The Sopranos\"?", "answer": "Peter Bogdanovich", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a554", "question": "Pierre is the capital of which US state?", "answer": "South Dakota", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c467", "question": "What is the proper term for a young eel?", "answer": "An elver", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a57b", "question": "US city Milwaukee is located on the shores of what lake?", "answer": "Lake Michigan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fec8b8bec223966ae8f883f", "question": "Who does the voice over for Dory from \"Finding Nemo\" and \"Finding Dory\"?", "answer": "Ellen DeGeneres", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e5b", "question": "What literary work inspired Dream Theater's \"Pull Me Under\" song?", "answer": "Hamlet", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a36f", "question": "What body of water does the Danube River flow into?", "answer": "The Black Sea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5901d901709c1c34536e6ea9", "question": "In what year did the Ultimate Fighting Championship start?", "answer": "1993", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388b0", "question": "Who wrote the Dark Tower series?", "answer": "Stephen King", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b98b", "question": "What is added to Gin to make Pink Gin?", "answer": "Angostura Bitters", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd8236cd0de9af39e9d46af", "question": "Which US First Lady was the first to give birth in the White House?", "answer": "Frances Cleveland", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59067e5aff9c0647b50a8079", "question": "What two American astronauts passed away in February of 2016?", "answer": "Edgar Mitchell and Donald E. Williams", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a43e", "question": "Greenland is part of which kingdom?", "answer": "Kingdom of Denmark", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5906814dff9c0647b50a8093", "question": "How old was novelist Harper Lee at the time of her death in February, 2016?", "answer": "89", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a00c", "question": "What two Orlando Magic teammates made their screen debuts in \"Blue Chips\"?", "answer": "Shaquille O'Neal and Anfernee Hardaway", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "601219ec63c99d48cd169afd", "question": "Who is the oldest man to win People Magazine\u2019s sexiest man alive?", "answer": "Sean Connery", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff51a51ff04d658268c9305", "question": "What philosophical tradition is associated with Jean-Paul Sartre?", "answer": "Existentialism", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be48", "question": "What word would best describe Port Salut?", "answer": "Cheese", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c202", "question": "Which country hosted the 1900 Olympic Games?", "answer": "France", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bb3", "question": "How many symphonies did Beethoven compose?", "answer": "9", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9c0", "question": "Which Nintendo character made the line \"Do a barrel roll!\" famous?", "answer": "Peppy", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58ab18bdbaab681b0929218e", "question": "Who is the world\u2019s largest tire manufacturer?", "answer": "LEGO", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a20b", "question": "Who sang the song \"Californication\"?", "answer": "Red Hot Chilli Peppers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe65f491f3c0ead6880d637", "question": "The word \"salary\" was inspired by people getting paid with what?", "answer": "Salt", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339224", "question": "Who celebrated is 111th birthday during \"The Lord of the Rings: The Fellowship of the Ring?\"", "answer": "Bilbo Baggins", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fec8421ec223966ae8f87fc", "question": "Which actor played Keyser S\u00f6ze's lawyer and confidant, Kobayashi?", "answer": "Pete Postlethwaite", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338939", "question": "What annual celebration is taking place at the start of \"Great Expectations\"?", "answer": "Christmas Eve", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b84f", "question": "What physical fitness practice is named for the Sanskrit word for \"union\"?", "answer": "Yoga", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad0d", "question": "Which popular Greek philosopher is said to have tutored Alexander the Great?", "answer": "Aristotle", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c65", "question": "Steven Spielberg's first full feature film as director was released in what year?", "answer": "1964", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "60078250bd51d85e222ab656", "question": "What did Claude Monet's father want him to be?", "answer": "Grocer (Monet's father disapproved of his painting. He wanted him to go into the family\u00a0grocery business.)", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c443", "question": "What direction do growing bananas point?", "answer": "Upwards", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c09b", "question": "What is the fear of knowledge known as?", "answer": "Epistemophobia or gnosiophobia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd2d0342596a59cbdfbd378", "question": "Who said, \"Nature has given us two ears, two eyes, and but one tongue-to the end that we should hear and see more than we speak\"?", "answer": "Socrates", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff2130931a458464a93c44d", "question": "What nationally-observed day in the U.S. marks winter's midpoint?", "answer": "Groundhog Day", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c456", "question": "Which bees in a hive are there to fertilize the queen?", "answer": "Drone bees", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cbe", "question": "What fairytale girl eats the window pane of the witch's cottage?", "answer": "Gretel", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ffa3bddc73aa70ea0b70ae9", "question": "Where is the Tomb of the Unknown Soldier located?", "answer": "Arlington National Cemetery, Virginia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339586", "question": "In the movie \"Young Frankenstein\", who played the role of the old blind man who invited the Monster into his cottage?", "answer": "Gene Hackman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bde7", "question": "What sport has thirteen players per team in \"league\" rules but fifteen in \"union\" play?", "answer": "Rugby", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a23", "question": "What name is usually given to Quasimodo who features in a French novel first published in 1831?", "answer": "The Hunchback of Notre Dame", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a45d", "question": "The island country Grenada is also known as what?", "answer": "Island of Spice", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9fc", "question": "What was Hawaii's main agricultural crop during the first half of the 20th century?", "answer": "Sugarcane", "category": "general"}, {"id": "60078261bd51d85e222ab657", "question": "What artist believed he was a reincarnation of his dead brother?", "answer": "When he was five, Dali's parents told him he was a reincarnation of his older brother, who died nine months before he was born.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a29d", "question": "Who starred as the male lead in the Alfred Hitchcock film \"To Catch a Thief\"?", "answer": "Cary Grant", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a22c", "question": "Who played the title role in the 1981 film \"Mad Max 2\"?", "answer": "Mel Gibson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ee8", "question": "What mythical title has been given to poets from Sappho to Anne Bradstreet?", "answer": "The Tenth Muse", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff3c1bc4f032c0db195b478", "question": "What tribe of Native Americans was the first to encounter the Pilgrims?", "answer": "The Wampanoag", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338947", "question": "What is the name for a literary device that combines two words and their definitions into a single new word?", "answer": "Portmanteau", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe7c3e1877e98cb97778998", "question": "What is the lowest elevation river in the world?", "answer": "Jordan River", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fef59cf6ce05a3942286e07", "question": "Where did the sport of curling originate?", "answer": "Scotland", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7e5", "question": "What element of the periodic table is named for a Jewish woman?", "answer": "Meitnerium", "category": "science"}, {"id": "595641ae803c1f1ebcc4a02a", "question": "The ball on top of a flag pole is called a what?", "answer": "Truck", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6000ed5a9a72b906b34e3ceb", "question": "Who invented the barometer in 1643?", "answer": "Evangelista Torricelli", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fedddba6ce05a3942286da6", "question": "How long did it take Markus \"Notch\" Persson to create the first version of \"Minecraft\"?", "answer": "Notch released the \"alpha version\" of \"Minecraft\" in just six days, with a fully-marketable version coming out two years later.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd3a", "question": "What poker hand are you holding if you have \"two fish-hooks\"?", "answer": "A pair of jacks", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff7c3fe2b316f4693fb67ac", "question": "What is the proper title for a person who makes pizzas in a pizzeria?", "answer": "A pizzaiolo", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5f178223b8195c09b948d5c3", "question": "What mythical creature is St. George said to have slain?", "answer": "A dragon", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af31", "question": "What organisation was given the only Nobel peace prize awarded during World War I?", "answer": "International Red Cross", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fdc11b0469bb8041d07a078", "question": "In Easter celebrations in Germany, what do children decorate trees with?", "answer": "Eggs", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5a4a990761d1b4d384d5d695", "question": "What year was the radio show \"Gunsmoke\" adapted for TV?", "answer": "1955", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5ed", "question": "Which grandmaster did Bobby Fischer defeat in 1972 and became the first American to win the world chess title?", "answer": "Boris Spassky", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338923", "question": "Which villain broke Batman's back?", "answer": "Bane", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a787", "question": "What important crop is the Rhine Valley in Germany known for growing?", "answer": "Grapes", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5b7abaff6490a8cc1a6e5293", "question": "In Roman numerals, what number does \"D\" represent?", "answer": "500", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393f4", "question": "What actor played the role of Korben Dallas in the 1997 movie \"The Fifth Element\"?", "answer": "Bruce Willis", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b172", "question": "What two architects are responsible for the design and construction of the Sistine Chapel?", "answer": "Baccio Pontelli and Giovannino de Dolci", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58dba3bb874c93a3298b213f", "question": "What was the full name of Queen Elizabeth The Queen Mother", "answer": "Elizabeth Angela Marguerite Bowes-Lyon", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c7a", "question": "What war is the setting for the novel \"All Quiet on the Western Front\"?", "answer": "World War I", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a86f", "question": "What language is spoken in the Pacific capital city of Yaren?", "answer": "Nauruan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2d8", "question": "What was the first man-made satellite put into orbit?", "answer": "Sputnik I", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6015dffffe83fe1f2a824b84", "question": "Which extinction event was caused by human activity?", "answer": "Holocene extinction", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391b6", "question": "Which movie popularized the phrase \"You had me at hello.\"?", "answer": "Jerry Maguire", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf87", "question": "Which male vocal range is pitched between tenor and bass?", "answer": "Baritone", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b374", "question": "What was the chief Roman silver coin?", "answer": "Denarius", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8ab", "question": "In what city would you find Battery Park?", "answer": "New York City", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca40", "question": "What is inflammation of the gums called?", "answer": "Gingivitis", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b31e", "question": "Constance Markievicz, became the first ever what In 1918?", "answer": "British female MP", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe6563cae7e414034b5aec4", "question": "Which two battleships remain buried following the attack on Pearl Harbor?", "answer": "USS Arizona and USS Utah", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad84", "question": "Who was the first Russian Czar to westernize Russia?", "answer": "Peter I", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe7c45f877e98cb9777899e", "question": "Which country was known as South West Africa until 1990?", "answer": "Namibia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a2", "question": "Who is known as Eminem?", "answer": "Marshall Mathers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59e6b28dfb6c85e9e634ff3f", "question": "Which years did Henry VI reign England?", "answer": "1422 to 1461 and 1470 to 1471", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b280", "question": "In what war did the oak-sided USS Constitution gain its nickname \"Old Ironsides\"?", "answer": "The War of 1812", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a370", "question": "What is the warmest continent?", "answer": "Africa", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd4e", "question": "The Edgar Award is an award given in what field?", "answer": "Mystery writing", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf24", "question": "What does the KonMari Method focus on?", "answer": "Tidying up", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5eb", "question": "What type of garment are \"Elephant bells\"?", "answer": "Pants", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393bd", "question": "What actor played Hunter S. Thompson in the movie \"Where The Buffalo Roam\"?", "answer": "Bill Murray", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59029f9bcad1ec93f27df762", "question": "What continent does yerba mate originates from?", "answer": "South America", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a913", "question": "In what US state would you find Fort Knox?", "answer": "Kentucky", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c77a", "question": "What large reptile was popularized by Steve Irwin and Paul Hogan?", "answer": "The crocodile", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0c8", "question": "Which TV character owns a talking cat called Salem?", "answer": "Sabrina Spellman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133affa", "question": "What general led the Confederates at the Battle of Gettysburg?", "answer": "General Robert E. Lee", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe7ca28877e98cb97778a03", "question": "In what sea would you find the Admiralty Islands?", "answer": "Bismarck Sea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c8f", "question": "What TV show takes place in the fictional city of Bedrock?", "answer": "The Flintstones", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fde492cc6c6b019850c9a6c", "question": "According to the Bible, what prophet was killed by being sawed in two inside a hollow log?", "answer": "Isaiah", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac31", "question": "What was the first railroad to cross the US?", "answer": "The Union Pacific", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe7350aeec85e375820b242", "question": "What was the name of President Lyndon B. Johnson's wife?", "answer": "Claudia Alta \"Lady Bird\" Johnson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fdc12d0469bb8041d07a07d", "question": "What direction should you stir your Christmas pudding according to tradition?", "answer": "East to West", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f95", "question": "Which word describing chaos first appeared in Milton's \"Paradise Lost\"?", "answer": "Pandemonium", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "60173fb844491cbd7c5a17b5", "question": "What was created by the people who produced the academic journal called the\u00a0\"Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists\" in 1947?", "answer": "The Doomsday Clock -- It was created after humanity entered the Nuclear Age after the dropping of atomic bombs on Japan in 1945.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdd7", "question": "What kind of cheese is most commonly sold in the US as processed \"string cheese\"?", "answer": "Mozzarella", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cad9", "question": "What was the common archaic name for a giraffe?", "answer": "Camelopard", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9b2", "question": "What team did Vince Lombardi coach to two Super Bowl victories?", "answer": "Green Bay Packers", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339742", "question": "Who was the youngest member of the Jackson 5?", "answer": "Michael Jackson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399db", "question": "What 2005 Gwen Stefani song was the first single to amass one million paid digital downloads?", "answer": "Hollaback Girl", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339086", "question": "What form of verse is \"Paradise Lost\" written in?", "answer": "Blank verse", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf13", "question": "What colour caps do the Australian cricket team wear?", "answer": "Green", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391b0", "question": "Who played the role of Andy Dufresne in the movie \"The Shawshank Redemption\"?", "answer": "Tim Robbins", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339af7", "question": "Not counting Elvis, what actor is mentioned by name in the Shania Twain song \"That Don't Impress Me Much\"?", "answer": "Brad Pitt", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58b8ce8d94b094db915830a8", "question": "What did the letters \u201cC\u201d and \u201cN\u201d originally stand for in Toronto\u2019s CN Tower", "answer": "Canadian National", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff0b498e662d71a53650fec", "question": "Which author wrote the \"Winnie-the-Pooh\" books?", "answer": "A. A. Milne", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5c028d0aea32143fcb1d3b55", "question": "In music, what is the term to gradually decrease in volume?", "answer": "Decrescendo", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fd66d47a5bfecdd737e089e", "question": "What is the most valuable stock exchange in the world?", "answer": "New York Stock Exchange", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391f9", "question": "In which 1998 movie did the main character said \"You got the wrong guy. I'm the Dude, man.\"?", "answer": "The Big Lebowski", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f7a", "question": "What was Jonathan Richman's backing band?", "answer": "The Modern Lovers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b00b", "question": "What duo explored the Pacific Northwest during the early 1800s?", "answer": "Lewis and Clark", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5febaae27e83c707845b20e3", "question": "Hydrargyrum was once the name for what element?", "answer": "Mercury", "category": "science"}, {"id": "60136faf138175489539637a", "question": "In 2000, what character was elected U.S. President in the DC universe?", "answer": "Lex Luthor", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5900887ecf842fa4c4ba9689", "question": "Who wrote the novel \"Across the River and into the Trees\"?", "answer": "Ernest Hemmingway", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133caec", "question": "Which planet has Prometheus as a satellite?", "answer": "Saturn", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd2d2a92596a59cbdfbd391", "question": "Equity State is the official nickname of which state?", "answer": "Wyoming", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac52", "question": "What was the first animal sent up to outer space?", "answer": "Dog", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a360", "question": "What city dug the first subway?", "answer": "London", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fedda356ce05a3942286d83", "question": "Who did Michael Jordan, as President of Basketball Operations for the Wizards, select with the first pick in the 2001 NBA Draft?", "answer": "Kwame Brown", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb06", "question": "Since 1949, what magazine has handed out the most prestigious \"Car of the Year\" Award?", "answer": "Motor Trend", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5a728c856bcd28c119383288", "question": "What is the first event in a Women's Heptathalon?", "answer": "100 Metres Hurdles", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a701", "question": "Which US state is home to the Inyo Mountains?", "answer": "California", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afc3", "question": "During what war did hundreds of soldiers spend the winter in Valley Forge?", "answer": "American Revolution", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d0f", "question": "What movie's first sequel featured the subtitle \"On the Move\"?", "answer": "Mannequin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339536", "question": "What TV show featured Ellen DeGeneres as a receptionist?", "answer": "Open House", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5feddb826ce05a3942286d90", "question": "In 1997 movie, \"Titanic\", what was the name of Rose's maid?", "answer": "Trudy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5b323658bf195a31e15d73ba", "question": "Which James Bond theme was a hit for Sheena Easton?", "answer": "For Your Eyes Only", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f45", "question": "Who created the character of Paddington?", "answer": "Michael Bond", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c833", "question": "What's the more common name for the retinal scotoma caused by the optic nerve?", "answer": "Your blind spot", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aab2", "question": "Which bird is the national bird of Belarus?", "answer": "White stork", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399fe", "question": "How many episodes of \"The X-Files\" were made?", "answer": "202", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6010c6e40775fa611bce67d4", "question": "A legislature that has legislators in two separate assemblies, chambers, or houses is called what?", "answer": "Bicameral", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b15b", "question": "What popular figure was born Agnese Gonxhe Bojaxhiu?", "answer": "Mother Teresa", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133982d", "question": "What musical follows the rivalry between the Jets and the Sharks in New York City?", "answer": "West Side Story", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe69fe920565ad31a57c792", "question": "What is the oldest-known epic tale?", "answer": "\"Epic of Gilgamesh\"", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fffa55273838c5c8a417f23", "question": "Who discovered the life or death importance of washing hands while studying maternity wards?", "answer": "Ignaz Philipp Semmelweis", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae00", "question": "Who took 18 days to write the Declaration of Independence?", "answer": "Thomas Jefferson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339246", "question": "What was the first album in history to reach number one in 34 nations?", "answer": "The Beatles 1", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339288", "question": "In the movie \"The Hunger Games\", what is Thresh's weapon of choice?", "answer": "A Scimitar", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca20", "question": "What are scaup?", "answer": "Ducks", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133969d", "question": "Ben Kingsley won an Oscar in 1982 for which movie directed by Richard Attenborough?", "answer": "Gandhi", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396f7", "question": "What were Moe Howard, Larry Fine and Curly Howard better known as?", "answer": "The 3 Stooges", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "600f700ea9e54d890926f6d4", "question": "South America\u2019s Atacama Desert holds what distinction?", "answer": "Driest non-polar desert -- Although it is home to about one million people, it records less than 1 mm of rain every year.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c754", "question": "What layer of the atmosphere is closest to the earth?", "answer": "The Troposphere", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5b323204bf195a31e15d738b", "question": "Belmopan is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Belize", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58d46fd6f8e329de4f87788a", "question": "Which actor's real name is Emanuel Goldenberg?", "answer": "Edward G. Robinson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afb3", "question": "Which Egyptian city was founded by Alexander the Great in 331 BC?", "answer": "Alexandria", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3db", "question": "What company introduced the first transistor-based hearing aid?", "answer": "Zenith", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6012155363c99d48cd169aea", "question": "In what year did Einstein receive his Nobel Prize for Physics? ", "answer": "1922 -- The prize was for 1921, but the Nobel Committee delayed presenting it for various reasons.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339221", "question": "Which two artists formed the band \"Wham!\"?", "answer": "George Michael and Andrew Ridgeley", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8b8", "question": "What word describes a handbag without straps or handles?", "answer": "Clutch", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c41b", "question": "What is the common word for a weight suspended from a pivot that can move freely?", "answer": "A pendulum", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388dd", "question": "What mythological beast has the head of a man, the body of a lion, and the tail and feet of a dragon?", "answer": "Manticore", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d4f", "question": "What actress shaved her head for her role in the movie \"THX 1138\"?", "answer": "Maggie McOmie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59e80658de59ea584496feb0", "question": "The character Smike appears in which Dickens novel?", "answer": "Nicholas Nickleby", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf5e", "question": "The Sejm are the legislative body in which country?", "answer": "Poland", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a077", "question": "In the TV series \"Leave It To Beaver\", what was Wally's best friend's name?", "answer": "Eddie Haskell", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c648", "question": "What is the name of Pluto's largest satellite?", "answer": "Charon", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af4c", "question": "In what year was the Sony Corporation founded?", "answer": "1946", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfc9", "question": "Nudophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Nudity", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e63", "question": "Who revealed he was HIV-positive in his 1995 autobiography \"Breaking the Surface\"?", "answer": "Greg Louganis", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe527021bf59ab7d2e380f8", "question": "Who was named as the athlete with the highest career earnings in 2017?", "answer": "Michael Jordan", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d59", "question": "What famed TV personality wrote the screenplay for 1968's \"Planet of the Apes\"?", "answer": "Rod Sterling", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0c1", "question": "What world leader sold the Louisiana Territory to the US?", "answer": "Napoleon Bonaparte", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ccf7b0eb37b32637bdc44c4", "question": "In what year was the first opera created?", "answer": "1597", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ffcfed09dc5ec6cd98a832c", "question": "What writer had more than 70 different pen names?", "answer": "Lauran Bosworth Paine", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b479", "question": "The Battle of the Plains of Abraham was fought outside of which North American city?", "answer": "Quebec City", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5a9e92d97ccba3ffe45786bd", "question": "Who wrote the 1932 comic novel \"Cold Comfort Farm\"?", "answer": "Stella Gibbons", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b71a", "question": "What is Santa's name in Spain?", "answer": "Papa Noel", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a106", "question": "What was the last film of director Stanley Kubrick?", "answer": "Eyes Wide Shut", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58c9f766b4e2c7fbd3896748", "question": "What company\u2019s tea shipment was destroyed during the Boston Tea Party in 1773?", "answer": "East India Company", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a243", "question": "Which character did David Jason play in the TV series \"Porridge\"?", "answer": "Blanco", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a93b", "question": "What US state is home to the singer of Stephen Foster's \"Oh! Susanna\"?", "answer": "Alabama", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5a9e95be7ccba3ffe45786e3", "question": "What do you add to Advocaat to make a Snowball\u00a0cocktail?", "answer": "Lemonade", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f6e", "question": "What can be a font, architectural style or novel type?", "answer": "Gothic", "category": "arts"}]